const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following correctly describes Kussmaul's sign?","answers":[{"option":"Paradoxical rise in the jugular venous pressure during inspiration","bool":true},{"option":"Paradoxical drop in the jugular venous pressure during expiration","bool":false},{"option":"Paradoxical rise in the jugular venous pressure during expiration","bool":false},{"option":"Paradoxical drop in the jugular venous pressure during inspiration","bool":false},{"option":"Paradoxical rise of the pulse rate during inspiration","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What is the most specific marker for myocardial infarction?","answers":[{"option":"Lactate dehydrogenase (LDH or LD)","bool":false},{"option":"Creatine phosphokinase-MB (CK-MB)","bool":false},{"option":"Creatine phosphokinase-BB (CK-BB)","bool":false},{"option":"Alkaline phosphatase","bool":false},{"option":"Troponin-I","bool":true}]},{"id":2,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Diastolic heart failure in a 65-year-old man is predominantly due to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Bilateral renal artery stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiomyopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertension","bool":true},{"option":"Diabetes mellitus","bool":false},{"option":"Obesity","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"A 4-year-old boy is brought by his parents with the complaint that he frequently catches a cold and gets cough. According to the parents, he had pneumonia thrice this year and had to be admitted to the hospital one time. On examination, an ejection systolic murmur is heard on the left upper sternal border with a fixed splitting of the second heart sound. The first heart sound is loud. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Patent ductus arteriosus","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial septal defect","bool":true},{"option":"Ventricular septal defect","bool":false},{"option":"Coarctation of aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Cystic fibrosis","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What is the pathogenesis of hyaline arteriosclerosis?","answers":[{"option":"Intake of extracellular calcium leading to hyperreactivity","bool":false},{"option":"Intimal degradation","bool":false},{"option":"Deposition of extracellular matrix","bool":true},{"option":"Medial hypertrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Atherosclerotic plaque disruptions","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"A murmur heard from right second intercostal space extending to the left sternal border is associated with what?","answers":[{"option":"Aortic stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Mitral stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Mitral regurgitation","bool":false},{"option":"Tricuspid regurgitation","bool":false},{"option":"Aortic regurgitation","bool":true}]},{"id":6,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following are minor manifestations of rheumatic fever according to Jones criteria?","answers":[{"option":"Purpuric rash and cough","bool":false},{"option":"Fever and tachycardia","bool":false},{"option":"Jaundice and edema","bool":false},{"option":"Migratory polyarthritis, carditis, subcutaneous nodules, erythema marginatum, Sydenham chorea","bool":false},{"option":"Fever and elevated erythrocyte sedimentation rate (ESR)","bool":true}]},{"id":7,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What does lidocaine do?","answers":[{"option":"Increase the amplitude of QRS complex","bool":false},{"option":"Increase action potential duration","bool":false},{"option":"Decrease conductivity","bool":false},{"option":"Increase PR interval","bool":false},{"option":"Reduce action potential duration","bool":true}]},{"id":8,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"A patient presents with an apex beat heaving with a thrill in the left 5th intercostal space. Which association is most likely?","answers":[{"option":"Mitral stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Mitral regurgitation","bool":true},{"option":"Pulmonic stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Tricuspid stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Tricuspid regurgitation","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"A continuous, \"machine-like\" murmur is associated with what congenital pathology?","answers":[{"option":"Coarctation of aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial septal defect","bool":false},{"option":"Teratology of Fallot","bool":false},{"option":"Ventricular septal defect","bool":false},{"option":"Patent ductus arteriosus","bool":true}]},{"id":10,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What congenital defect is rubella most commonly associated with?","answers":[{"option":"Atrial septal defect","bool":false},{"option":"Teratology of Fallot","bool":false},{"option":"Bicuspid aortic valve","bool":false},{"option":"Patent ductus arteriosus","bool":true},{"option":"Coarctation of aorta","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"An atrial septal defect is most strongly associated with what chromosomal syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Down syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Turner syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Edwards syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Williams syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Patau syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What is the most common cause of right heart failure (RHF)?","answers":[{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Orthopnea","bool":false},{"option":"Left heart failure (LHF)","bool":true},{"option":"Septal defects","bool":false},{"option":"Cor pulmonale","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"A patient presents with a complaint of exertional chest pain. Which of the following substances mediates this pain?","answers":[{"option":"Interleukin","bool":false},{"option":"Epinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Serotonin","bool":false},{"option":"Histamine","bool":false},{"option":"Adenosine","bool":true}]},{"id":14,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What would be the most effective preventive measure in the population to decrease the risk of cardiac disease?","answers":[{"option":"Weight loss","bool":false},{"option":"Stress management","bool":false},{"option":"Management of hypertension","bool":false},{"option":"Increase physical activity","bool":false},{"option":"Dietary and lifestyle changes","bool":true}]},{"id":15,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"A 65-year-old patient with a recent history of myocardial infarction presents with acute shortness of breath. On examination, he has a pansystolic murmur at the mitral area and an audible S3 heart sound. Bi-basilar inspiratory crackles are also heard on inspiration. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Mitral stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Pericarditis","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Mitral regurgitation","bool":true},{"option":"Aortic stenosis","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following does not cause cor pulmonale?","answers":[{"option":"Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD)","bool":false},{"option":"Right heart failure secondary to left heart failure","bool":true},{"option":"Pulmonary embolism","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary hypertension","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What is the mechanism of action of nitroglycerin?","answers":[{"option":"Decrease both cAMP and cGMP","bool":false},{"option":"Increases cAMP","bool":false},{"option":"Decreases cGMP","bool":false},{"option":"Decreases cAMP","bool":false},{"option":"Increases cGMP","bool":true}]},{"id":18,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following agents is preferred in hypertensive emergencies?","answers":[{"option":"Sodium nitroprusside","bool":true},{"option":"Amiodarone","bool":false},{"option":"Clonidine","bool":false},{"option":"Diazoxide","bool":false},{"option":"Propranolol","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"A 2-year-old baby had congenital heart disease. Which syndrome is most commonly associated with congenital heart disease?","answers":[{"option":"DiGeorge syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Rubella syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Klinefelter syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Down syndrome","bool":true}]},{"id":20,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is true regarding atrial septal defect?","answers":[{"option":"It is the commonest congenital cardiac anomaly","bool":false},{"option":"It usually causes death before puberty if untreated","bool":false},{"option":"It is associated with trisomy 21","bool":true},{"option":"It is twice as common in males as compared to females","bool":false},{"option":"It does not lead to pulmonary hypertension","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"'Sign of 3' is a feature of which congenital disease of the heart?","answers":[{"option":"Atrial septal defect","bool":false},{"option":"Persistent truncus arteriosus","bool":false},{"option":"Patent ductus arteriosus","bool":false},{"option":"Tetralogy of Fallot","bool":false},{"option":"Coarctation of aorta","bool":true}]},{"id":22,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"A 48-year-old female presents to the emergency department with a bleeding nose and high blood pressure. Upon physical examination, hypertension in upper limbs but hypotension in lower limbs is noticed. Which of the following conditions has the patient developed?","answers":[{"option":"Infundibular pulmonary stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial septal defect","bool":false},{"option":"Patent ductus arteriosus","bool":false},{"option":"Tetralogy of Fallot","bool":false},{"option":"Coarctation of aorta","bool":true}]},{"id":23,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"A 2-month-old baby presents with poor feeding and respiratory distress. Physical examination reveals normal pulses, but a pansystolic murmur is heard at the left sternal angle. The baby is also tachypneic, with hepatomegaly and marked cardiomegaly. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Atrial septal defect","bool":false},{"option":"Transposition of the great arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Tetralogy of Fallot","bool":false},{"option":"Ventricular septal defect","bool":true},{"option":"Truncus arteriosus","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"A 5-year-old child is found to have a pansystolic murmur that is best heard at the left sternal edge and radiates all over the precordium. Which of the complications is most likely to develop in this child?","answers":[{"option":"Aortic dissection","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial fibrillation","bool":false},{"option":"Systemic hypertension","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary hypertension","bool":true},{"option":"High grade fever","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"A 30-year-old patient is identified with hypertension in his upper extremities and hypotension in his lower extremities. His X-ray shows notches on his ribs. What is the most likely condition ssociated with his presentations?","answers":[{"option":"Coarctation of the aorta","bool":true},{"option":"Atrial septal defect","bool":false},{"option":"Tetralogy of Fallot","bool":false},{"option":"Patent ductus arteriosus","bool":false},{"option":"Infundibular pulmonary stenosis","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following diseases does not have left to right shunt, hence does not cause Eisenmenger syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Tetralogy of Fallot","bool":true},{"option":"Ventricular septal defect (VSD)","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial septal defect (ASD)","bool":false},{"option":"Atrioventricular defect (AVSD)","bool":false},{"option":"Patent ductus arteriosus (PDA)","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What is the mechanism of action of heparin?","answers":[{"option":"Catalyzes the binding of antithrombin III","bool":true},{"option":"Blocks protein kinase A","bool":false},{"option":"Increases cGMP","bool":false},{"option":"Increases cAMP","bool":false},{"option":"Decreases hepatic synthesis of vitamin K dependent factors","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What is the appearance of a tissue that has undergone myocardial infarction (MI) 8 hours ago?","answers":[{"option":"Red and swollen with early necrosis","bool":true},{"option":"Coagulation necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Scar tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Tissue with neutrophil infiltrate","bool":false},{"option":"Gray-white scar","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What is the time taken by the myocardial infarction to complete scarring?","answers":[{"option":"1 month","bool":false},{"option":"3 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"14 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"2 months","bool":true},{"option":"12 days","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following congenital defect causes reversal of the shunt (from left to right to right to left) and hence Eisenmenger syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Large patent ductus arteriosus (PDA)","bool":true},{"option":"Tricuspid atresia","bool":false},{"option":"Coarctation of the aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Transpositions of great vessels","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following correctly describes atrial septal defect?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"A congenital cyanotic defect between left and right atria","bool":false},{"option":"A congenital non-cyanotic defect between left and right ventricles","bool":false},{"option":"A congenital non-cyanotic defect between left and right atria","bool":true},{"option":"A congenital cyanotic defect between left and right ventricles","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"A 41-year-old man is diagnosed with congenital heart disease. He had no symptoms early in his life. What could be the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Ventrcular septal defect","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial septal defect","bool":true},{"option":"Tetralogy of Fallot","bool":false},{"option":"Patent ductus arteriosus","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"A ventricular septal defect is most commonly associated with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Aortic regurgitation","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Mitral stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Teratology of Fallot","bool":true},{"option":"Mitral regurgitation","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Nitroglycerin is contraindicated in which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Arterial constriction","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertensive emergency","bool":false},{"option":"Raised intracranial pressure","bool":true},{"option":"Renal artery stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Headache","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Pulmonary hypertension is caused by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Mitral stenosis","bool":true},{"option":"Tricuspid atresia","bool":false},{"option":"Tricuspid stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonic stenosis","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What is the most common cause of mitral valve prolapse?","answers":[{"option":"Hypertrophic cardiomyopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Marfan syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Tricuspid valve prolapse","bool":false},{"option":"Hydropic degeneration","bool":false},{"option":"Myxomatous degeneration","bool":true}]},{"id":37,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following food items is rich in saturated fats?","answers":[{"option":"Yoghurt","bool":false},{"option":"Animal fat","bool":true},{"option":"Eggs","bool":false},{"option":"Canola oil","bool":false},{"option":"Spinach","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What is the most common cause of abdominal aortic aneurysms?","answers":[{"option":"Trauma","bool":false},{"option":"Vascular wall abnormalities","bool":false},{"option":"Atherosclerosis","bool":true},{"option":"Hypertension","bool":false},{"option":"Vasculitis","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What is the name of the point which adjoins the QRS complex and the ST segment?","answers":[{"option":"A point","bool":false},{"option":"X descent point","bool":false},{"option":"X point","bool":false},{"option":"J point","bool":true},{"option":"C wave point","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"A patient presents with chest pain that increases on inspiration and lying down and is relieved when leaning forward. What is the most likely pathology?","answers":[{"option":"Bacterial myocarditis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute pericarditis","bool":true},{"option":"Cardiac tamponade","bool":false},{"option":"Mitral stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Bacterial endocarditis","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Concurrent administration of quinidine and digoxin results in drug-drug interaction. How does quinidine interact with digoxin?","answers":[{"option":"Synergistic effect on myocardium","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibits the metabolism of digoxin","bool":false},{"option":"Antagonized the effect of digoxin on the A-V node","bool":false},{"option":"Increased serum concentration of digoxin","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased the absorption of digoxin in GIT","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What mechanism of action allows the use of digoxin in atrial fibrillation?","answers":[{"option":"Slows down AV node conduction","bool":true},{"option":"Speeds up AV node conduction","bool":false},{"option":"Increases SA node firing","bool":false},{"option":"Increases myocardium contractility","bool":false},{"option":"Decreases myocardium contractility","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What type of cells are anitschkow cells?","answers":[{"option":"Eosinophils","bool":false},{"option":"Macrophages","bool":true},{"option":"T-lymphocytes","bool":false},{"option":"B-lymphocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Erythrocytes","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"How many total set of valves does a normal heart contain?","answers":[{"option":"5","bool":false},{"option":"2","bool":false},{"option":"3","bool":false},{"option":"1","bool":false},{"option":"4","bool":true}]},{"id":45,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Suppurative pericarditis with subsequent scarring leads to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Serous pericarditis","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrinous pericarditis","bool":false},{"option":"Adhesive mediastinopericarditis","bool":false},{"option":"Constrictive pericarditis","bool":true},{"option":"Myopericarditis","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Atrial fibrillation most commonly occurs as a complication of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Hypertrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Myocardial infarction","bool":false},{"option":"Mitral stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperthyroidism","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertension","bool":true}]},{"id":47,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"A 50-year-old lady with a known case of rheumatoid arthritis for the last 15 years, develops lethargy, exertional dyspnea, collapsing radial pulse, visible nail bed, and carotid pulsation in the neck. On chest auscultation, high pitched early diastolic murmur is heard. What is the most likely valvular abnormality she is suffering from?","answers":[{"option":"Aortic stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Mitral regurgitation","bool":false},{"option":"Mitral stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Aortic regurgitation","bool":true}]},{"id":48,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following organisms is involved in the pathogenesis of rheumatic fever?","answers":[{"option":"Streptococcus viridians","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus agalactiae","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pyogenes","bool":true},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is true for mitral stenosis?","answers":[{"option":"Opening snap sound","bool":true},{"option":"Mid-diastolic murmur","bool":false},{"option":"Machine like murmur","bool":false},{"option":"Mid-systolic murmur","bool":false},{"option":"Holosystolic murmur","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following statements is incorrect?","answers":[{"option":"The inferior border of the heart extends from the 6th right costal cartilage to the apex","bool":false},{"option":"Apex beat is palpated on left intercostal space lateral to mid clavicular line","bool":true},{"option":"Mitral sounds are best heard at apex","bool":false},{"option":"Apex beat is palpated on left intercostal space medial to mid clavicular line","bool":false},{"option":"The left border of the heart is formed by the left ventricle","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following will lead to an apex beat auscultated lateral to midclavicular line in the 6th intercostal space?","answers":[{"option":"Right ventricle dilatation","bool":false},{"option":"Right atrium dilatation","bool":false},{"option":"Left ventricle dilatation","bool":true},{"option":"Left ventricle hypoplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Left atrium hypoplasia","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following findings would indicate a high-risk factor prediction while performing the exercise tolerance test (ETT)?","answers":[{"option":"3 mm Hg drop in diastolic blood pressure","bool":false},{"option":"5 mm Hg drop in systolic blood pressure","bool":false},{"option":"1 mm ST elevation in V2-V6","bool":false},{"option":"2 mm ST depression in inferior leads","bool":true},{"option":"Upsloping ST depression of 3 mm in V2-V6","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"A patient has a systolic murmur in the aortic area. Which of the following is a character of this murmur?","answers":[{"option":"Crescendo","bool":false},{"option":"Diamond-shaped","bool":true},{"option":"Holosystolic","bool":false},{"option":"Triangular","bool":false},{"option":"Decrescendo","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following conditions will show a crescendo-decrescendo murmur?","answers":[{"option":"Mitral regurgitation (MR)","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial septal defect (ASD)","bool":false},{"option":"Ventricular septal defect (VSD)","bool":false},{"option":"Aortic stenosis (AS)","bool":true},{"option":"Hypertrophic cardiomyopathy (HCM)","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"A 46-year-old male patient is being given an anti-arrhythmic drug post-myocardial infarction to suppress premature ventricular contractions. As a result, he develops seizures. Which of the following conditions has he developed?","answers":[{"option":"Ventricular tachycardia","bool":false},{"option":"Ventricular asystole","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial fibrillation","bool":false},{"option":"Atropine toxicity","bool":false},{"option":"Lidocaine toxicity","bool":true}]},{"id":56,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following anti-arrhythmic drugs causes constipation as a side effect?","answers":[{"option":"Atenolol","bool":false},{"option":"Quinidine","bool":false},{"option":"Lidocaine","bool":false},{"option":"Propanolol","bool":false},{"option":"Verapamil","bool":true}]},{"id":57,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which one of the following is a potassium channel activator?","answers":[{"option":"Metoprolol","bool":false},{"option":"Clonidine","bool":false},{"option":"Methyldopa","bool":false},{"option":"Diazoxide","bool":true},{"option":"Tolbutamide","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following drugs is contraindicated in variant angina?","answers":[{"option":"Diltiazem","bool":false},{"option":"Verapamil","bool":false},{"option":"Beta-blockers","bool":true},{"option":"Nifedipine","bool":false},{"option":"Nitroglycerine","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is preferably given for relief in acute variant angina?","answers":[{"option":"Propanolol","bool":false},{"option":"Diltiazem","bool":false},{"option":"Nifedipine","bool":true},{"option":"Isosorbide","bool":false},{"option":"Atenolol","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is an adverse effect of procainamide?","answers":[{"option":"Anemia","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial fibrillation","bool":false},{"option":"Torsades de pointes","bool":true},{"option":"Hypertension","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Procainamide is used for which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Aortic stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Right-sided heart failure","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial fibrillation","bool":true},{"option":"Left-sided heart failure","bool":false},{"option":"Left ventricular hypertrophy","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following class of drugs operates by activating guanylate cyclase and increasing cGMP?","answers":[{"option":"Ranolazine","bool":false},{"option":"Digoxine","bool":false},{"option":"Milrinone","bool":false},{"option":"Nitrates","bool":true},{"option":"Amlodipine","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"A patient taking a class of antihypertensives complains about side effects of severe dry cough. Which of the following drugs is causing the dry cough?","answers":[{"option":"Atenolol","bool":false},{"option":"Diltiazem","bool":false},{"option":"Verapamil","bool":false},{"option":"Captopril","bool":true},{"option":"Propanolol","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of these drugs has a moderate blocking effect on phase 0 of the cardiac action potential?","answers":[{"option":"Lidocaine","bool":false},{"option":"Atenolol","bool":false},{"option":"Flecainide","bool":false},{"option":"Amiodarone","bool":false},{"option":"Quinidine","bool":true}]},{"id":65,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is the neurological disorder as a result of rheumatic fever?","answers":[{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Painless lumps (nodules)","bool":false},{"option":"Sydenham chorea (SC)","bool":true},{"option":"Erythema marginatum","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following drugs is not contraindicated in pregnancy?","answers":[{"option":"Propranolol","bool":false},{"option":"Captopril","bool":false},{"option":"Atenolol","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Methyldopa","bool":true}]},{"id":67,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following represents Duke's major criteria?","answers":[{"option":"One blood culture positive and echocardiographic changes","bool":false},{"option":"Two blood cultures positive and echocardiographic changes","bool":true},{"option":"Echocardiographic changes only","bool":false},{"option":"Fever and immunologic phenomena","bool":false},{"option":"Fever and predisposing heart condition","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is the characteristic cell of rheumatic fever?","answers":[{"option":"Aschoff bodies","bool":true},{"option":"Epithelioid cells","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Charcot Leyden crystals","bool":false},{"option":"Curschmann spirals","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which class of drugs are 3-hydroxy-3-methyl-glutaryl-coenzyme A reductase (HMG CoA reductase) inhibitors?","answers":[{"option":"Nitrates","bool":false},{"option":"Statins","bool":true},{"option":"Fibrates","bool":false},{"option":"Bile acid sequestrants","bool":false},{"option":"Niacin","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is an alpha-2 agonist?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Terbutaline","bool":false},{"option":"Phenylephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Clonidine","bool":true},{"option":"Dobutamide","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following drugs converts plasminogen to plasmin?","answers":[{"option":"Alteplase","bool":true},{"option":"Aminocaproic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Warfarin","bool":false},{"option":"Streptokinase","bool":false},{"option":"Heparin","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following correctly defines idiosyncrasy?","answers":[{"option":"Adverse effects that generally occur in the majority of population","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Adverse effects that are infrequent and sporadically seen among the population even with low dosages","bool":true},{"option":"Exaggerated immune response","bool":false},{"option":"Widespread allergic response","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following antihypertensives is safe to use in pregnancy?","answers":[{"option":"Benazepril","bool":false},{"option":"Atenolol","bool":false},{"option":"Methyldopa","bool":true},{"option":"Metolazone","bool":false},{"option":"Captopril","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is correct about mitral valve prolapse?","answers":[{"option":"Commonly associated with apical chest pain","bool":false},{"option":"Is a condition associated with high risk of embolic stroke or TIA","bool":false},{"option":"Produces ejection click and early systolic murmur","bool":false},{"option":"Is caused by congenital anomalies or degenerative myxomatous changes","bool":true},{"option":"Is associated with a variety of lethal arrhythmias","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding a typical second heart sound?","answers":[{"option":"Helps in diagnosis of atrial septal defect","bool":false},{"option":"Best heard with the bell of stethoscope","bool":true},{"option":"Quantifies pulmonary pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Best heard in 2nd left intercostal space","bool":false},{"option":"Normally it splits during inspiration","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is the main indication for coronary artery bypass graft (CABG)?","answers":[{"option":"Single vessel disease","bool":false},{"option":"Three-vessel disease","bool":true},{"option":"Double-vessel disease","bool":false},{"option":"Aortic dissection","bool":false},{"option":"Stable angina","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is a side effect of angiotensin-converting enzyme (ACE) inhibitors?","answers":[{"option":"Renal artery stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Hypokalemia","bool":false},{"option":"Agranulocytosis","bool":true},{"option":"Hypertension","bool":false},{"option":"Proteinuria","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is the most common cause of reversed splitting of S2?","answers":[{"option":"Severe aortic stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Right bundle branch block","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertrophic obstructive cardiomyopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Right ventricular branch block","bool":false},{"option":"Left bundle branch block","bool":true}]},{"id":79,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which vasculitis involves the aorta?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Takayasu disease","bool":true},{"option":"Giant cell arteritis","bool":false},{"option":"Behcet disease","bool":false},{"option":"Polyarteritis nodosa","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which kind of cells form the foam cells?","answers":[{"option":"Dendritic cells","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Eosinophils","bool":false},{"option":"Macrophages","bool":true},{"option":"Histiocytes","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"In which of the following is the sinoatrial node present?","answers":[{"option":"Right atrium","bool":true},{"option":"Right ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"Left ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Left atrium","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"A 46-year-old woman suffering from obesity is traveling from Pakistan to USA. She starts experiencing shortness of breath. Which of the following could be a likely reason?","answers":[{"option":"Pericarditis","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary embolism","bool":true},{"option":"Hyperlipidemia","bool":false},{"option":"Aortic dissection","bool":false},{"option":"Acute coronary syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What is the length of the PR interval?","answers":[{"option":"0.2 s","bool":true},{"option":"0.1 s","bool":false},{"option":"0.5 s","bool":false},{"option":"0.4 s","bool":false},{"option":"0.3 s","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is increased in tuberculous pericardial effusions?","answers":[{"option":"Monocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Neutrophils","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphocytes","bool":true},{"option":"Basophils","bool":false},{"option":"Eosinophils","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Anitschkow cells are seen in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Rheumatic pancarditis","bool":true},{"option":"Constrictive pericarditis","bool":false},{"option":"Rheumatic endocarditis","bool":false},{"option":"Infective endocarditis","bool":false},{"option":"Myocardial infarction","bool":false}]},{"id":86,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is the most common cause of atrial fibrillation?","answers":[{"option":"Myocardial infarction","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertension","bool":true},{"option":"Hyperthyroidism","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Mitral stenosis","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"The Jones criteria is used to diagnose which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Pericarditis","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Myocardial infarction","bool":false},{"option":"Rheumatic fever","bool":true},{"option":"Endocarditis","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following leads to constrictive cardiomyopathy in transfusion dependent thalassemia?","answers":[{"option":"Hemochromatosis","bool":true},{"option":"Anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hemolysis","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoxia","bool":false},{"option":"Tachycardia","bool":false}]},{"id":89,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following commonly develops in the second trimester of pregnancy?","answers":[{"option":"Restrictive cardiomyopathy","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Arrhythmogenic right ventricular cardiomyopathy (ARVC)","bool":false},{"option":"Dilated cardiomyopathy","bool":true},{"option":"Hypertrophic cardiomyopathy (HCM)","bool":false}]},{"id":90,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"A 16-year-old soccer player collapses on the ground in the middle of a game from sudden heart failure. What is the most likely cause?","answers":[{"option":"Sinoatrial rhythm","bool":false},{"option":"Bundle branch block","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial fibrillation","bool":false},{"option":"Ventricular fibrillation","bool":true},{"option":"Atrial tachycardia","bool":false}]},{"id":91,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is used as diagnostic criteria for acute pericarditis?","answers":[{"option":"Murmur on expiration","bool":false},{"option":"No pericardial effusion","bool":false},{"option":"Pericardial friction rub","bool":true},{"option":"Normal electrocardiogram findings","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false}]},{"id":92,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is the major risk factor for aortic dissection?","answers":[{"option":"Atherosclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Aneurysm","bool":false},{"option":"Marfan syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertension","bool":true}]},{"id":93,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is the most common primary tumor of the heart?","answers":[{"option":"Papillary fibroelastoma","bool":false},{"option":"Fibroma","bool":false},{"option":"Myxoma","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Rhabdomyoma","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"A 10-year-old child presents to the emergency with palpitations. On examination, he has an irregular radial pulse and a murmur best heard at the apex of the heart. Which of the following is the cause for the murmur?","answers":[{"option":"Mitral valve regurgitation","bool":false},{"option":"Ventricular fibrillation","bool":false},{"option":"Heart block","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial fibrillation","bool":true},{"option":"Pulmonic stenosis","bool":false}]},{"id":95,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What is the length of nasogastric tube that should be inserted during gastric lavage?","answers":[{"option":"30 cm","bool":false},{"option":"35 cm","bool":false},{"option":"50 cm","bool":true},{"option":"40 cm","bool":false},{"option":"20 cm","bool":false}]},{"id":96,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is the contraindication in the left bundle branch block (LBBB)?","answers":[{"option":"Thallium scan","bool":false},{"option":"CT angiography","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiac MRI","bool":false},{"option":"Dobutamine stress echo","bool":false},{"option":"Exercise stress testing (ETT)","bool":true}]},{"id":97,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following diseases is caused by genetic causes?","answers":[{"option":"Infective endocarditis","bool":false},{"option":"All of them","bool":false},{"option":"Cor pulmonale","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertrophic cardiomyopathy","bool":true},{"option":"Carcinoid heart disease","bool":false}]},{"id":98,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following cardiac dysfunction is seen in restrictive cardiomyopathy?","answers":[{"option":"Systolic dysfunction","bool":false},{"option":"It has no effect on systolic or diastolic function of the heart","bool":false},{"option":"Diastolic dysfunction","bool":true},{"option":"Systolic dysfunction that converts to diastolic with increasing severity","bool":false},{"option":"Both systolic and diastolic dysfunction","bool":false}]},{"id":99,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What is the term used to describe an acid attack?","answers":[{"option":"Corrosive attack","bool":false},{"option":"Grievous injury","bool":false},{"option":"Vitriolage","bool":true},{"option":"Sexual assault","bool":false},{"option":"Mounting injury","bool":false}]},{"id":100,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is a major cause of restrictive cardiomyopathy?","answers":[{"option":"Tumors","bool":false},{"option":"Ventricular septal defect","bool":false},{"option":"Amyloidosis","bool":true},{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Myocarditis","bool":false}]},{"id":101,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What effect do somniferous poisons have?","answers":[{"option":"Hyperventilation","bool":false},{"option":"Diuresis","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperthermia","bool":false},{"option":"Sleep induction","bool":true},{"option":"Tachycardia","bool":false}]},{"id":102,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is present in atherosclerotic plaque?","answers":[{"option":"Magnesium","bool":false},{"option":"Cholesterol","bool":true},{"option":"All of them","bool":false},{"option":"HDL","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphocytes","bool":false}]},{"id":103,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is not related to the causes of atherosclerosis?","answers":[{"option":"Smoking","bool":false},{"option":"Hypercholesterolemia","bool":false},{"option":"Increased low-density lipoprotein (LDL)","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertension","bool":false},{"option":"Increased high-density lipoprotein (HDL)","bool":true}]},{"id":104,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following should not be used as an antidote for sulphuric acid?","answers":[{"option":"Sodium bicarbonate","bool":true},{"option":"Limewater","bool":false},{"option":"All of these can be used","bool":false},{"option":"Magnesium oxide","bool":false},{"option":"Milk of magnesia","bool":false}]},{"id":105,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Saturated fatty acids increase the risk of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Malignancy","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiovascular disease","bool":true},{"option":"Stroke","bool":false},{"option":"Hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary embolism","bool":false}]},{"id":106,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"A person presents to the outpatient department with the complaint of increased blood pressure. On examination, his blood pressure is 160/100 mmHg, and is declared to have hypertension. What is the mean arterial pressure in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"120 mmHg","bool":true},{"option":"110 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"150 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"130 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"90 mmHg","bool":false}]},{"id":107,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following signs confirms drowning?","answers":[{"option":"Cadaveric spasm","bool":false},{"option":"Distended lungs","bool":false},{"option":"Froth from mouth","bool":true},{"option":"Cutis anserina","bool":false},{"option":"Clenched fists","bool":false}]},{"id":108,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is a pulseless disease?","answers":[{"option":"Aortic regurgitation","bool":false},{"option":"Tricuspid atresia","bool":false},{"option":"Atherosclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiomyopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Takayasu's arteritis","bool":true}]},{"id":109,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is not a contraindication of gastric lavage?","answers":[{"option":"Carbolic acid","bool":true},{"option":"Unprotected airway","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrocarbon poisoning","bool":false},{"option":"Corrosive poisoning","bool":false},{"option":"Ingestion of sharp objects","bool":false}]},{"id":110,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following can cause ST segment depression?","answers":[{"option":"Pericarditis","bool":false},{"option":"Subendocardial ischemia","bool":true},{"option":"Myocardial infarction","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Prinzmetal angina","bool":false}]},{"id":111,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is most likely to cause infectious endocarditis in an intravenous (IV) drug abuser?","answers":[{"option":"Streptococcus viridans","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus saprophyticus","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":true},{"option":"Streptococcus bovis","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus epidermidis","bool":false}]},{"id":112,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Hyperlipidemia is associated with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Diabetes","bool":false},{"option":"Sedentary lifestyle","bool":false},{"option":"Obesity","bool":false},{"option":"High-fat diet","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":true}]},{"id":113,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What is the name given to the poisons which act primarily on nervous system?","answers":[{"option":"Neurotoxins","bool":false},{"option":"Neurotic poisons","bool":true},{"option":"Peripheral nervous system toxins","bool":false},{"option":"Neural poisons","bool":false},{"option":"Central nervous system toxins","bool":false}]},{"id":114,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Hyperkalemia causes which change in an electrocardiogram?","answers":[{"option":"Narrow QRS complex","bool":false},{"option":"U waves","bool":false},{"option":"Widened QRS complex","bool":true},{"option":"Small P waves","bool":false},{"option":"Flattened T waves","bool":false}]},{"id":115,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following blood vessels return blood from the body to the heart?","answers":[{"option":"Aorta and superior vena cava","bool":false},{"option":"Superior vena cava and inferior vena cava","bool":true},{"option":"Pulmonary artery and inferior vena cava","bool":false},{"option":"Left main coronary artery","bool":false},{"option":"Aorta and pulmonary artery","bool":false}]},{"id":116,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Cannon “a” waves in jugular pulse indicate which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"2nd degree heart block","bool":false},{"option":"Tricuspid stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary hypertension","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Complete heart block","bool":true}]},{"id":117,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Juxtaglomerular cells are present in which structure of the kidney?","answers":[{"option":"Collecting duct","bool":false},{"option":"Proximal convoluted tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Collecting tubules","bool":false},{"option":"Glomerulus","bool":false},{"option":"Afferent arteriole","bool":true}]},{"id":118,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"A worker in a calico-printing industry is fired from his job and attempts suicide by ingesting an easily available organic acid at the factory. 30 minutes later, he is found in a state of shock with coffee-ground colored vomitus, severe pain in the throat and abdomen, and twitching of muscles. Which of the following is the most likely organic acid used for attempted suicide?","answers":[{"option":"Nitric acid","bool":false},{"option":"Acetic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Sulfuric acid","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrochloric acid","bool":false},{"option":"Oxalic acid","bool":true}]},{"id":119,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Blackening of the stomach, abdominal distension, and chalky white teeth are caused by the ingestion of which of the following mineral acids?","answers":[{"option":"Hydrofluoric acid","bool":false},{"option":"Nitric acid","bool":false},{"option":"Oxalic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrochloric acid","bool":false},{"option":"Sulfuric acid","bool":true}]},{"id":120,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What is the action of digitalis?","answers":[{"option":"Increased contraction of ventricles","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased automaticity of atria","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Increased refractory period of AV node","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased excitation of atria","bool":false}]},{"id":121,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Digitalis is used in atrial fibrillation due to which reason?","answers":[{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Muscarinic activity","bool":false},{"option":"AV nodal delay","bool":true},{"option":"Cholinergic activity","bool":false},{"option":"Increased cardiac output","bool":false}]},{"id":122,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"For variant (Prinzmetal angina), which of the following drug would be most appropriate for long-term therapy aimed at reducing the incidence or severity of coronary vasospasm?","answers":[{"option":"Statins","bool":false},{"option":"Diltiazem","bool":true},{"option":"Nitroglycerin","bool":false},{"option":"Propranolol","bool":false},{"option":"Aspirin","bool":false}]},{"id":123,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"A young male drug abuser with a history of hepatitis (HBV), presents with hypertension, abdominal pain, melena, muscle aches, and skin nodules. The laboratory test confirms HbsAg and pANCA positivity. Which one of the following describes the histopathologic appearance of the vasculitis in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Granulomatous inflammation with presence of giant cells","bool":false},{"option":"Cystic medial degeneration","bool":false},{"option":"Segmental transmural necrotizing inflammation","bool":true},{"option":"Necrotizing and granulomatous inflammation","bool":false},{"option":"Transmural fibrous thickening","bool":false}]},{"id":124,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is a selective beta-1 agonist drug?","answers":[{"option":"Amrinone","bool":false},{"option":"Digoxin","bool":false},{"option":"Dopamine","bool":false},{"option":"Digitoxin","bool":false},{"option":"Dobutamine","bool":true}]},{"id":125,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Oligemic lung fields on X-ray chest are seen in which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Tetralogy of Fallot","bool":true},{"option":"Atrial septal defect","bool":false},{"option":"Mitral stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Tricuspid regurgitation","bool":false},{"option":"Ventricular septal defect","bool":false}]},{"id":126,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is the mechanism of action of statins?","answers":[{"option":"Inhibiting conversion of HMG CoA to cholesterol","bool":true},{"option":"Inhibit the metabolism of acetyl CoA","bool":false},{"option":"Binds with bile acids","bool":false},{"option":"Increase the metabolism of cholesterol","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibit the conversion of cholesterol in VLDL","bool":false}]},{"id":127,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Anticoagulants are given after which of the following mitral valve surgeries?","answers":[{"option":"Transcatheter Aortic Valve Replacement (TAVR)","bool":false},{"option":"Bioprosthetic valve replacement","bool":false},{"option":"Balloon valvuloplasty","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Mechanical valve replacement","bool":true}]},{"id":128,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What amount of charcoal is required as an antidote?","answers":[{"option":"60-100 gm","bool":true},{"option":"2-4 gm","bool":false},{"option":"5-10 gm","bool":false},{"option":"15-30 gm","bool":false},{"option":"100-200 gm","bool":false}]},{"id":129,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"In which type of poisoning is stomach wash not contraindicated?","answers":[{"option":"Hydrochloric acid","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Carbolic acid","bool":true},{"option":"Carboxylic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Sulfuric acid","bool":false}]},{"id":130,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"In which kind of poisoning is a bone sample obtained?","answers":[{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Corrosive","bool":false},{"option":"Heavy metals","bool":true},{"option":"Diarrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Organic acid","bool":false}]},{"id":131,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"In a private clinic in Lahore, a cholera epidemic has broken out. The doctor will call which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Health authorities","bool":true},{"option":"Area magistrate","bool":false},{"option":"The police","bool":false},{"option":"Hospital incharge","bool":false}]},{"id":132,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following drugs has to be taken by a patient for a lifetime after mechanical replacement surgery of the mitral valve?","answers":[{"option":"Vitamin K1","bool":false},{"option":"Coumarin","bool":true},{"option":"Streptokinase","bool":false},{"option":"Heparin","bool":false},{"option":"Aspirin","bool":false}]},{"id":133,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following can be used for the diagnosis of rheumatic fever?","answers":[{"option":"Arthralgia with fever and raised ESR","bool":false},{"option":"Arthralgia with prolonged PR fever","bool":false},{"option":"Carditis with arthralgia and fever","bool":true},{"option":"Arthralgia only","bool":false},{"option":"Arthralgia with fever","bool":false}]},{"id":134,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is the gold standard for the diagnosis of constrictive pericarditis?","answers":[{"option":"Chest X-ray","bool":false},{"option":"Echocardiography","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"CT scanning","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiac catheterization","bool":true}]},{"id":135,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is one of the principal components of an atherosclerotic plaque?","answers":[{"option":"Predominantly eosinophils","bool":false},{"option":"Macrophages","bool":true},{"option":"Amyloid","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrinous material","bool":false},{"option":"Epithelioid cells","bool":false}]},{"id":136,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What is the percentage of coronary artery stenosis in typical angina?","answers":[{"option":"50%","bool":false},{"option":"10%","bool":false},{"option":"20%","bool":false},{"option":"90%","bool":true},{"option":"40%","bool":false}]},{"id":137,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"A 60-year-old man comes to the clinic with complaints of breathlessness and chest pain on exertion for 1 year. On examination, the blood pressure is 110/90 mm Hg. A crescendo-decrescendo murmur is heard over the right upper sternal border during systole. What is the likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Mitral stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Aortic stenosis","bool":true},{"option":"Aortic regurgitation","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary regurgitation","bool":false},{"option":"Tricuspid regurgitation","bool":false}]},{"id":138,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"A 30-year-old female presents to the clinic for routine examination. Chest auscultation reveals an ejection systolic murmur that radiates to the left sternal border and a soft P2 sound. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Atrial septal defect","bool":false},{"option":"Tricuspid regurgitation","bool":false},{"option":"Aortic stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary stenosis","bool":true},{"option":"Mitral regurgitation","bool":false}]},{"id":139,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"A 55-year-old woman presents to the emergency department with sudden onset of chest pain. An ECG shows ST-segment elevations in leads II, III, avF, V4, V5, and V6. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Anterolateral MI","bool":false},{"option":"Inferolateral MI","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior wall MI","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior wall MI","bool":false},{"option":"Anteroseptal MI","bool":false}]},{"id":140,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"A 64-year-old male with hypertrophic obstructive cardiomyopathy and a previous history of MI presents to the clinic with a complaint of recurrent syncope. Echocardiogram shows an increase in left ventricular wall thickness from last year. \r\nWhich of the following is the most suitable option to prevent sudden cardiac death in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"β-blockers","bool":false},{"option":"Septal ablation","bool":false},{"option":"Diltiazem","bool":false},{"option":"Implantable cardioverter-defibrillator (ICD)","bool":true},{"option":"Digoxin","bool":false}]},{"id":141,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following types of shock is characterized by warm peripheries?","answers":[{"option":"Cardiogenic shock","bool":false},{"option":"Obstructive shock","bool":false},{"option":"Septic shock","bool":false},{"option":"Distributive shock","bool":true},{"option":"Hypovolemic shock","bool":false}]},{"id":142,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"A 51-year-old patient presents to the emergency department with chest pain. An ECG shows ST-segment elevation. On examination, there is sinus bradycardia. How can heart rate be increased?","answers":[{"option":"Verapamil","bool":false},{"option":"Atropine","bool":true},{"option":"Clonidine","bool":false},{"option":"Epinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Dopamine","bool":false}]},{"id":143,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What would be the preferred initial management for a condition with an ECG showing paroxysmal bouts of normal but irregular QRS complexes with no P waves?","answers":[{"option":"Defibrillation","bool":false},{"option":"Amiodarone","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium channel blockers","bool":false},{"option":"Digoxin","bool":false},{"option":"Beta-blockers","bool":true}]},{"id":144,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"An electrocardiogram of a patient shows tachycardia and broad, abnormal QRS complexes with a rate of more than 120 beats/min, with a blood pressure of 90/60 mmHg. What is the most appropriate treatment?","answers":[{"option":"Beta-blockers","bool":false},{"option":"Amiodarone","bool":false},{"option":"Quinidine","bool":false},{"option":"Synchronised DC cardioversion","bool":true},{"option":"Digoxin","bool":false}]},{"id":145,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"A patient presents to the emergency with typical chest pain of 3 hours duration. Electrocardiogram shows an ST-segment elevation What will be the most appropriate treatment?","answers":[{"option":"Fondaparinux","bool":false},{"option":"Percutaneous coronary intervention","bool":true},{"option":"Coronary artery bypass graft","bool":false},{"option":"Heparin","bool":false},{"option":"Thrombolysis","bool":false}]},{"id":146,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"A 41-year-old patient visits the clinic. He has a history of diabetes for the last 8 years. He has a persistently elevated blood pressure of 160/100 mmHg. What is the most appropriate antihypertensive?","answers":[{"option":"Thiazide diuretics","bool":false},{"option":"Nitroprusside","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium channel blockers","bool":false},{"option":"Angiotensin converting enzyme inhibitors or angiotensin receptor blockers","bool":true},{"option":"Beta-blockers","bool":false}]},{"id":147,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"A young man presents to the hospital with a history of hypertrophic obstructive cardiomyopathy. What will be the best initial management for him?","answers":[{"option":"Reassurance","bool":false},{"option":"Alcohol (non surgical) ablation of the septum","bool":false},{"option":"Dual chamber pacing","bool":false},{"option":"Implantable cardioverter defibrillator (ICD)","bool":false},{"option":"Beta blockers","bool":true}]},{"id":148,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What would be the treatment of New York Heart Association classification class III heart failure?","answers":[{"option":"Diuretics, angiotensin converting enzyme inhibitors and beta blockers","bool":true},{"option":"Ivabradine only","bool":false},{"option":"Spironolactone and diuretics","bool":false},{"option":"Diuretics and angiotensin receptor blockers","bool":false},{"option":"Digoxin","bool":false}]},{"id":149,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following drugs should be used for rate control in atrial fibrillation?","answers":[{"option":"Digoxin","bool":false},{"option":"Amiodrone","bool":false},{"option":"Beta blockers","bool":true},{"option":"Lisinopril","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrochlorothiazide","bool":false}]}]
export default arr